<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Nathan Laundry&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Nathan Laundry&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 20:09:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ABScribe: Rapid Exploration of Multiple Writing Variations in Human-AI Co-Writing Tasks using Large Language Models</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/abscribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 20:09:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/abscribe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Accepted at CHI 2024&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.00117&#34;&gt;Pre-Print&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Github: &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;ABScribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exploring alternative ideas by rewriting text is integral to the writing process. State-of-the-art large language models (LLMs) can simplify writing variation generation. However, current interfaces pose challenges for simultaneous consideration of multiple variations: creating new versions without overwriting text can be difficult, and pasting them sequentially can clutter documents, increasing workload and disrupting writers&amp;rsquo; flow. To tackle this, we present ABScribe, an interface that supports rapid, yet visually structured, exploration of writing variations in human-AI co-writing tasks. With ABScribe, users can swiftly produce multiple variations using LLM prompts, which are auto-converted into reusable buttons. Variations are stored adjacently within text segments for rapid in-place comparisons using mouse-over interactions on a context toolbar. Our user study with 12 writers shows that ABScribe significantly reduces task workload (d = 1.20, p &amp;lt; 0.001), enhances user perceptions of the revision process (d = 2.41, p &amp;lt; 0.001) compared to a popular baseline workflow, and provides insights into how writers explore variations using LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IN-COURSE EXPERIENCES WITH A SCIOER FOR OBJECT-ORIENTED PROGRAMMING</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/scioer-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 20:09:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/scioer-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://library.iated.org/view/NELSON2023INC&#34;&gt;Link Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract-and-intro&#34;&gt;Abstract and Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;STEM learners often find benefit from interactive resources that provide a tutorial-like environment that facilitate guided practice. However, such resources are frequently expensive, and learners are not permitted to retain permanent copies. Online interactive resources are often not completely aligned with the learning outcomes for a class. Instructors may adopt more than one resource to provide a complete set of materials for students, which can increase both the financial burden and the cognitive load for students who must then pay for access to multiple resources and remember which resource to use in each context. Additionally, most interactive resources require the learner to maintain a high-speed network connection to the resource. For learners in rural or remote areas, a high-speed internet requirement might be impossible to meet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a Computational Thinking Paradigm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/masters-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 20:09:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/masters-thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Master&amp;rsquo;s Thesis&lt;br&gt;&#xA;PDF: [Toward a Computational Thinking Paradigm](Designing, Deploying, and Analyzing Adaptive Educational Field Experiments)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Computational Thinking (CT) is crucial in today’s world, but the lack of a shared paradigm poses challenges for researchers addressing key issues like effective teaching. Diverse stakeholder motivations further complicate consensus on definitions, methods, and metrics. This research proposes a CT meta-framework, integrating cognitive science and stakeholder hypotheses, to disambiguate definitions and clarify experimental methods for a CT transfer experiment. The framework’s success is measured by its ability to disambiguate transfer and algorithm definitions, determine an algorithmic thinking metric, and design a transfer case study method. The research involves three steps: 1) literature review and coding to identify CT per- spectives and provide nomenclature for them; 2) integrating cognitive science concepts to develop the CT meta-framework; and 3) applying the meta-framework in a transfer case study to disambiguate definitions and identify limitations. This research aims to bridge the gap between CT perspectives and facilitate a more cohesive approach to CT research and education.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SCIOER Course : C Programming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/scioer-c-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 20:09:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/scioer-c-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://yc-prod-openlibrary-repo.ecampusontario.ca/jspui/handle/123456789/1786&#34;&gt;Available Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This resource is part of an investigation into a semi-automated process for creating Self-Contained, Interactive Open Educational Resources (SCIOER) for use by students and instructors in the discipline of Computer Science. Resources created through the SCIOER process are self-contained and provide all the tools necessary for learners. The interactive nature of the resource encourages experimentation and incremental practice. Learners are able to annotate SCIOER resources with their personal observations and learnings. The SCIOER C Programming course is provided as a docker image (&lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/r/scioer/c-programming&#34;&gt;https://hub.docker.com/r/scioer/c-programming&lt;/a&gt;) The docker container provides a fully interactive e-text for programmers who wish to improve their knowledge of the C programming language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using A/B Testing as a Pedagogical Tool for Iterative Design in HCI Classrooms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/abtesting-as-a-pedagogical-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 20:09:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/abtesting-as-a-pedagogical-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Submitted to EduCHI-2023&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Find it Here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/pdf/10.1145/3587399.3587412?casa_token=ATNfXt0EASIAAAAA:dePM7KyqP-_FfsdgpSBQospHdtYrsexpQ1C6r3YdHo4SoefjctyCrcqb643YRR2ncEa0LKGgtmehZ7s&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This paper explores the use of A/B testing as a pedagogical tool&lt;br&gt;&#xA;for iterative design in HCI classrooms and outlines a vision for&lt;br&gt;&#xA;experiment-inspired design. The traditional focus on the statistical&lt;br&gt;&#xA;aspects of A/B testing education has meant that the equally crucial&lt;br&gt;&#xA;role of iterative design embedded within the experimental process&lt;br&gt;&#xA;has not received commensurate attention. By incorporating iter-&lt;br&gt;&#xA;ative design learning activities that are scaffolded by A/B testing&lt;br&gt;&#xA;tools, HCI students can gain transferable skills and experience in do-&lt;br&gt;&#xA;ing multiple cycles of ideation, prototyping, testing, and evaluation,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and simultaneously contribute to continual course improvement.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We reconsider the role of experimentation in HCI education as&lt;br&gt;&#xA;a means for exploring complex design spaces. Drawing from our&lt;br&gt;&#xA;experience in teaching this approach and conducting education&lt;br&gt;&#xA;research involving sequences of online controlled experiments, we&lt;br&gt;&#xA;present examples of how to use A/B testing as a pedagogical tool&lt;br&gt;&#xA;for iterative design in HCI classrooms&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Online Gaming Communities: From Features to Emergent Behaviours to Online Communities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/buidling-online-gaming-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 20:09:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/buidling-online-gaming-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1jZgUw4aBWC4MJocizFBiDQwtWmx2Gp2G/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Unpublished PDF Available here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Players form meaningful communities via online games. Game developers can retain players if they support online communities.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;However, existing literature often does not provide actionable advice on how to build online communities and insights gathered&lt;br&gt;&#xA;may only be relevant for one game or one genre of games. Through consolidating existing literature, we found that it may be the&lt;br&gt;&#xA;behaviours that emerged (Emergent Behaviours) that create online communities. To determine if Emergent Behaviours can directly&lt;br&gt;&#xA;lead to online gaming communities, we conducted seven semi-structured online interviews with players of World of Warcraft and&lt;br&gt;&#xA;StarCraft. Our interviews revealed seven Emergent Behaviours that can help form online gaming communities and the 13 Feature&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Categories (with example features) developers can build to foster the Emergent Behaviours in their games&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Smells as a Framework for Automated Feedback for Novice Programmers - ICERI2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/code-smells-as-a-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 20:09:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/code-smells-as-a-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;[Full Paper Here](https://library.iated.org/view/LAUNDRY2021COD)&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Students who receive high quality, rapid feedback about their work are advantaged. The absence of feedback within a reasonable timeline can reinforce incorrect learning, instigate student frustration, and ultimately lead to student disengagement. Automated feedback has been shown to be an effective tool that can scale easily to large class sizes and has positive impacts on student learning. Existing feedback mechanisms for computer programmers such as messages produced by compilers and linters are cryptic and not aimed at novice coders. Furthermore, these existing tools do not attempt to address programming design issues, rather they simply point out a potential error in the code without explantion about why the error is problematic or what the underlying misconception might be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing, Deploying, and Analyzing Adaptive Educational Field Experiments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/designing-deploying-analyzing-educational-field-experiments-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 20:09:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/designing-deploying-analyzing-educational-field-experiments-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SIGCSE 2023&lt;br&gt;&#xA;LINK: &lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3545947.3569635&#34;&gt;Designing, Deploying, and Analyzing Adaptive Educational Field Experiments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digital experiments can be used in CSedu to test hypotheses about interventions and conditions&amp;rsquo; efficacy (or inefficacy). This workshop will discuss and deconstruct the design process and analysis for various experiments conducted in CS1. E.g., experiments testing which explanations students find helpful, which emails get them to start homework early, or which webpages effectively encourage and motivate students. This workshop teaches participants how to conduct, interpret, and analyze adaptive field experiments. These adaptive experiments employ machine learning algorithms to analyze experiments during deployment and dynamically shift the allocation of arms/conditions to give future students better conditions more rapidly. Adaptive field experiments can accelerate scientific discovery by enabling more complex experimental designs and increasing statistical power by phasing conditions in and out more efficiently. The workshop is supported by a 5-year NSF grant to build software tools and a digital community, gathering instructors, domain scientists and methodologists to teach them how to run adaptive experiments. The methodological focus includes understanding: (1) which algorithms are best for adaptive experiments that meet domain scientists&amp;rsquo; needs in specific experimental designs and data sets; (2) which hypothesis tests and Bayesian analyses to choose. Software companies use these innovative methodologies extensively to continuously improve product design. This workshop demonstrates how the same methods can be used in CSedu to improve research rigor and accelerate educational research implementation, ultimately improving student outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
