<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shower-Thoughts on Nathan Laundry&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shower-Thoughts on Nathan Laundry&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 12:02:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why the Kobo Rocks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/kobo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 12:02:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/kobo/</guid>
      <description>Growing up, I was much more into Call of Duty than reading which I&amp;rsquo;ve heard is equally valid and useful to you later in life so shut up. Luckily for me, at some point Call of Duty began to suck and I started a masters degree that forced me to read. Naturally, as a 22/23 year old who was vaguely into tech and productivity, when prompted with the query &amp;ldquo;how read book tech?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Point of Dance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/the-point-of-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/the-point-of-dance/</guid>
      <description>I can dance if I want to&#xA;I don’t dance. Never have. And i’m adamant that I can’t.&#xA;To no fault of my loving and accepting parents, I grew up a little repressed.&#xA;Some people refer to it as “Gifted Kid” syndrome. Personally, I was never given the title but I over-achieved and felt that paralyzing need to be correct - more than any authority figure could ever place on me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s the Comforts That Make us Feel Numb.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/its-the-comforts-that-make-us-feel-numb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 20:09:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/its-the-comforts-that-make-us-feel-numb/</guid>
      <description>I heard once, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the comforts that make us feel numb&amp;rdquo; - Hozier&#xA;And you know what? I think he&amp;rsquo;s right.&#xA;I think the ways in which we save time, the little eases and comforts, the ergonomics of our lives numb us and erode our sense of meaning. Now, does that mean I churn my own butter and sew my own clothes? Of course not, but it does make me think about the little moments that make up my life and how they make up my sense of meaning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop Trying to Remember Everything you Read.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/stop-trying-to-remember-everything-you-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 20:09:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/stop-trying-to-remember-everything-you-read/</guid>
      <description>Stop Trying to Remember Everything you Read. The Having vs Being fallacy of digital second brains and remembering everything you read I was seduced by the Capture Everything, Remember Everything you read, Digital Brain, trend for 2 years. You know what it got me? A Notion AND Roam Research so full I&amp;rsquo;m terrified of looking through them and a long list of books I&amp;rsquo;ve speed read but can barely recall.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turn GPT-4 Into your Personal Literature Review Bot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/chatgpt-litreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/chatgpt-litreview/</guid>
      <description>👋 Hey Friends, Getting into a new field of research requires reading dozens of landmark and seminal papers to understand that field’s foundations. This usually involves the manual process of searching key-words on google scholar, finding papers, polling friends, advisors, colleagues, and other experts for the most important papers. It’s an ad-hoc process that can take months.&#xA;Even more time intensive is conducting a proper, methodical, literature review. Establishing a method, identifying the correct keywords, finding the right databases - it’s difficult but vital work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prime then Immerse: How I Learn Difficult Things Quickly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/prime-then-immerse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/prime-then-immerse/</guid>
      <description>💡If you want to learn French, move to France.&#xA;🧑‍💻 How I Learned Terminal Driven Linux This is my mantra and it all started in 2016, my first year as a Computer Science Undergrad at the University of Guelph. I had been looped in by SOCIS — the Society of Computing and Information Sciences — which sounds a lot more official than it really was. At the time, it was a small community of fellow geeks, nerds, and tech enthusiasts (it’s grown to be much larger than that these days) and the cool thing was Linux.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Journey Through Reductionism and Determinism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/reductionism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/reductionism/</guid>
      <description>👋 Hey Friends, Some kids grow up wanting to be firefighters, astronauts, or teachers … I wanted to be Laplace’s Demon. Let me explain.&#xA;Pierre Simon Laplace hypothesized:&#xA;if we knew both the laws of physics and the location of every particle in the universe, we would be able to predict everything that would happen in the future. — Paraphrasing Pierre Simon Laplace on Laplace’s demon&#xA;Laplace attributed these powers to an imagined demon with almost infinite intellect.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Overcome a Fear of Writing: A Programmer&#39;s Perspective</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/fear-of-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/fear-of-writing/</guid>
      <description>🔥 “I hate writing and I never want to do it again.” — Nathan Laundry 2013 to 2020&#xA;And I’m not alone. In Computer Science a lot of us wear our disdain for writing as a badge of honour. Honestly, there’s a sense of comradery in our shared hate for writing. I’d go so far as to say, in the undergrad’s natural habitat — the lecture hall — you can identify Computer Science students by the distinct groan they emit when an essay is assigned.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconnecting a New Graduate Student Community Post-Covid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/gradstudent-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/gradstudent-community/</guid>
      <description>Tldr; 📧 What Canadian Computer Science Lost in the COVID Years&#xA;📣 How the Loss of Pillar Events will be Felt by our Communities&#xA;📶 Connection for Graduate Computer Science Students&#xA;🦋 Emergent research ideas: how connectivity leads to inspiration&#xA;💔 The Splintering of Research Communities&#xA;🔗 How do we Un-Splinter The COVID Generation of Researchers?&#xA;📲 Concluding: a Call to Action&#xA;📧 What Canadian Computer Science Lost in the COVID Years We’ve all read enough “Covid sucks and here’s why” articles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 9–5 Graduate Student Schedule: Why I Treat Research Like any Other Job</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/9-5gradschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/9-5gradschool/</guid>
      <description>Between 33% and 46% of Ph.D. Students don’t complete their degree [1].&#xA;I don’t know about you, but that sends shivers down my spine. In my reading and previous article on how to succeed with one’s doctoral pursuits, we discussed the many ways that professors have seen graduate students fail to finish their degrees. While most agree on the big things: write consistently, learn by doing, don’t aim too high or low, a major point of contention was time management.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Your Surface Area for Serendpity: Finding Opportunities as a Computer Science Undergrad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/csundergrad-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/csundergrad-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>🏃🏽 TLDR — How to find summer research opportunities and freelance programming jobs for undergraduates There is a huge unfulfilled need for programmers outside of the tech-sphere both in research and in industry&#xA;How to find research and freelance opportunities outside of the usual places:&#xA;Go to events and join clubs&#xA;Teach, tutor, and be taught&#xA;Say yes to opportunities wherever you find them&#xA;Opportunities to look out for:&#xA;Data is plentiful and in need of analysis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surviving Grad School: What they don&#39;t tell you in Undergrad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/surving-grad-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/surving-grad-school/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I’m Nathan. Hope this little Grad School Survival guide helps :)&#xA;Check out my other work at Nathanlaundry.com&#xA;The TLDR on how to survive your master’s/phd&#xA;Priortize your research, not your grades Listen to your advisors but know when to take the lead Don’t read too much (there is a sweet spot) Learn by problem-solving Don’t leave all your writing to the end As I approach the end of my first year as a graduate student, I’ve begun to look forward; crafting a path towards a successful thesis and setting up for my PhD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Write your own HCI Related Works Section Template</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/how-to-write-your-own-lit-review-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/how-to-write-your-own-lit-review-template/</guid>
      <description>What you’ll find here&#xA;My process for figuring out what to include in a literature review The template I built for writing future literature reviews So recently I had to write a literature review for one of my classes and I wanted to formalize my approach to doing so. I’ve been working on it for the past few days and thought I’d share what I’ve done so any new graduate students, like myself, can learn from it and hopefully share their own tips and tricks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ponder Walks and Wander Walks: Thinking on the Go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/ponder-and-wander-walks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shower-thoughts/ponder-and-wander-walks/</guid>
      <description>👋 Hey Friends, So, I’ve decided to try to write more short articles. I’ve realized that my perfectionist tendencies have crept in once again and are keeping me from posting more frequently. I’ve got a backlog of ideas that I keep tinkering with hoping one day they’ll be good enough to share. This little article is the first in an attempt to share the imperfect. Here’s a little idea I had on walks and how they facilitate thinking.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
