<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on Nathan Laundry&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://example.org/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on Nathan Laundry&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 20:09:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Execute shell commands from inside Vim</title>
      <link>https://example.org/tech/execute_sh_commands_from_vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 20:09:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/tech/execute_sh_commands_from_vim/</guid>
      <description>Vim has some really useful but lesser known features that can be really useful when creating temporary shell scripts. In this tech quickie post, I use Vim :&#39;&amp;lt;,&#39;&amp;gt;! syntax to help me quickly define an entire project in Taskwarrior - a CLI for task and project management.&#xA;Visually Select a Set of Lines In my case, I was setting a series of tasks to port my docker server from Ubuntu to Debian - a subset of the task are listed below.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turn GPT-4 Into your Personal Literature Review Bot</title>
      <link>https://example.org/tech/chatgpt-litreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/tech/chatgpt-litreview/</guid>
      <description>👋 Hey Friends, Getting into a new field of research requires reading dozens of landmark and seminal papers to understand that field’s foundations. This usually involves the manual process of searching key-words on google scholar, finding papers, polling friends, advisors, colleagues, and other experts for the most important papers. It’s an ad-hoc process that can take months.&#xA;Even more time intensive is conducting a proper, methodical, literature review. Establishing a method, identifying the correct keywords, finding the right databases - it’s difficult but vital work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT is my Writing Coach and Editor: Here&#39;s How</title>
      <link>https://example.org/tech/chatgpt-writing-coach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/tech/chatgpt-writing-coach/</guid>
      <description>💡 Truly great writing, the kind that moves us, comes from lived human experiences. This will always be the domain of Sapiens. — A trust me bro statement by Nathan Laundry&#xA;ChatGPT doesn’t have its own stories to share, but it excels at finding mistakes in the ways I write about mine! That’s why ChatGPT and I make a great team. I bring real stories and ChatGPT helps me convey them effectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.org/tech/hugo_site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/tech/hugo_site/</guid>
      <description>#DRAFT&#xA;goldmark in hugo.toml&#xA;unsafe = true gives me html which is useful for newlines with </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
