<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Nathan Laundry&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://example.org/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Nathan Laundry&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The 9–5 Graduate Student Schedule: Why I Treat Research Like any Other Job</title>
      <link>https://example.org/shower-thoughts/9-5gradschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/shower-thoughts/9-5gradschool/</guid>
      <description>Between 33% and 46% of Ph.D. Students don’t complete their degree [1].&#xA;I don’t know about you, but that sends shivers down my spine. In my reading and previous article on how to succeed with one’s doctoral pursuits, we discussed the many ways that professors have seen graduate students fail to finish their degrees. While most agree on the big things: write consistently, learn by doing, don’t aim too high or low, a major point of contention was time management.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Your Surface Area for Serendipity - CUSEC 2023</title>
      <link>https://example.org/talks/increasing-your-surface-area-for-serendipity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/talks/increasing-your-surface-area-for-serendipity/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ponder Walks and Wander Walks: Thinking on the Go</title>
      <link>https://example.org/shower-thoughts/ponder-and-wander-walks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/shower-thoughts/ponder-and-wander-walks/</guid>
      <description>👋 Hey Friends, So, I’ve decided to try to write more short articles. I’ve realized that my perfectionist tendencies have crept in once again and are keeping me from posting more frequently. I’ve got a backlog of ideas that I keep tinkering with hoping one day they’ll be good enough to share. This little article is the first in an attempt to share the imperfect. Here’s a little idea I had on walks and how they facilitate thinking.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
